Hello, I'm your host David Bernard and
my guest today is Tim Dyken, chief
operating officer of
teaching.com. On the podcast, I talk
with Tim about the importance of trust
in web to app funnels, replacing free
trials with money back guarantees, and
how they found success with contractors
after struggling with in-house marketing
hires. Hey Tim, thanks so much for
joining me on the podcast today. Yeah,
absolutely. Pleasure to be here. So,
we're going to talk about teaching.com,
reading.com, nitroype, typing.com. Uh,
you got a lot of great brands. And
interestingly, and I didn't know this
till you and I started making notes for
the for the podcast, that the company
started in 1997.
So the the success you see today is what
is that 28 years in the making which
it's crazy how many you know storied
brands are now finally doing well. I
think you you all were maybe earlier
than some of those older brands to
mobile and to consumer success. But it's
really cool to be talking to someone at
a company that's been around 28 years
and is doing really well in this new age
of mobile. Tell us a little bit about
the story of Teaching.com and
Reading.com. Like you said, things
started in the late 90s. The founder,
Austin Butler, was working at a a
community college at the like computer
lab cuz back in the day there were
computer labs. And someone approached
him and and asked if the computers had
typing software on them. And he's like,
"No, but you know, he was kind of aware
of what the capabilities of the internet
were." And he's like, "I'm sure you can
find something on the internet." And the
kid went and looked and then came back a
few minutes later and said I couldn't
find anything on the internet. And so
Austin went and taught himself how to
program, bought a DHTML and JavaScript
book and and built the the web's first
typing tutor as a it was typing webb.net
back in the day. And so he kind of ran
that as a side hustle for a while and
did other kind of software engineering
things. And then in the early 2000s, it
had generated kind of enough organic
interest that he decided to try and make
that a thing and kind of went full full
on into into trying to build the the
typing tutor. And then we started
launching additional products. In 2011,
we launched uh Nitro Type, which was a a
real-time competitive typing game played
by middle schoolers across the country.
And that was really really successful as
well. And then in
2022, I believe January of 22 is when we
launched Reading.com, which both typing
and nitro are primarily like B2B
products. We sell the software directly
to K12 institutions. And with
Reading.com, we wanted to to sell
directly to the consumers. So it's our
our first foray into kind of BTOC apps.
And it was our first mobile app as well.
Well, not not technically our first
mobile app. There was uh, you know, part
of this success story early on, right
when the first, you know, app store came
out had this idea for an app called text
pics where you could copy and paste ask
art and send it back and forth cuz, you
know, all iPhones had the same font. And
so, even though it wasn't a monospace
font, it would show up the same way on
both the sender and the receiver. And so
he he built this little 99 cent app and
and put it on the app store and it just
blew up. It was featured by Apple a
bunch of times back when that really
mattered and generated quite a bit of of
revenue that was then able to kind of
turn around and invest back into the
actual educational app side of things
and that that kind of had its heyday. It
came came and went and then yeah we got
back into the the app space with uh
reading.com. Yeah, such an awesome
story. As a company, you have found
product market fit across three or four
different products and in two different
kind of distinct industries. I mean B2B
I mean not technically B2B the way we
typically think of B2B SAS but like
edtech I guess it may be a better
category to put it in. You know edtech
and selling to schools is such a
different skill set such a different
kind of product requirements. you know,
you're building a product to satisfy the
the RFP for I don't know even know what
they call it now at schools, but like to
satisfy the the school requirements and
to sell to administrators and then to
now be running a consumer company where
you're like primary target is a
consumer. It's just honestly
fascinating, incredible to me that
you've found success across that many
different products across such disperate
industries. So I wanted to talk a little
bit about how teaching.com thinks about
the company about building products
because I think that really is key to
having found that kind of success. So
how do you think about building
products? A lot of different directions
to go with that. The mission statement
that we have here at teaching.com is
just to to build cool stuff that helps a
ton of kids, right? And we think about
ourselves not as an education company
but as a product company because at the
end of the day we're builders. what
really matters to us, what's really fun
for us is to build cool products. And so
we're kind of always thinking about the
user and the use case and not
necessarily chasing features that would
close a deal, but really trying to think
through what the users actually want. We
hear what they're asking for, but what
do they really need? I think there's
some pretty distinct things about the
way we run the company. Like for
instance, we're async first, right? So
we don't use Slack here. We consider it
a productivity killer. It encourages
this always on behavior and the kind of
the conveyor belt of text where if
you're not on right now, if you miss a
conversation, it's gone, right? And so
what we do is we we use different tools
that really help slow down the pace of
of conversation and facilitate people
thinking through things more deeply
before they post them. And that has been
really fantastic in improving the
quality and the thought process behind
everything that we do. So how how do you
get out of that? What tools do you use?
So we we use Base Camp for everything
mostly. And so we actually do use Slack,
but we intentionally have the free
version where like past 90 days of
history everything's deleted. What we do
when we're onboarding new folks, we say
we want you to use Base Camp and we want
you to disable all notifications. So you
shouldn't be getting any desktop
notifications or email notifications or
phone like nothing, right? And so when
you log into Base Camp, it's more of a
of a push, right? Like you're you're
intentionally going to it because right
now is the time that you have structured
your day, right? We want folks to be to
have large blocks of uninterrupted time
to do deep work and then when you come
up for air, you might log into Base Camp
and see what's been going on there. And
then we use Slack and we say, "Okay, you
do need to turn your notifications on in
case I do need to get a hold of you
right now. If I'm blocked on something
or someone else is blocked on something
and I can unblock them, I want them to
reach out to me immediately in real
time." But we police that pretty heavily
so that if you're reaching out to me on
Slack, it better be because you either
need to tell me something right now or
you need the answer from me right now.
any other reason should be in base camp
and I will get to it when I get to it
when it's convenient for me. And that
really opens up space for people to do
really great work and then only they're
not constantly context switching because
of notifications and whatnot. Man, I
really like
that at our scale and and the habits
that have been formed over the the eight
years as a company. I've been there six
years now. sounds very hard to kind of
change gears at this point, but
definitely sounds like a very nice way
to work. And for those who can maybe
make the transition, the proof is in the
pudding. You know, the results speak for
themselves. Sounds like you guys have
built fantastic products operating that
way. And it seems like a really great
way to build fantastic products. But
let's get back to kind of the way
Teaching.com thinks about building
products. I know on your website you
have a whole manifesto and we don't need
to go point by point through that but
maybe give us a summary of the manifesto
and then how that kind of plays out in
product decisions in messaging in in the
way the company runs and thinks about
product. Yeah. Gosh, you're right. I
think that document is probably four
pages or something. So there's a lot of
content in there. We originally put it
out there just because we're very
opinionated about the way we work and
the way we think about things and we
wanted to make sure that people who
wanted to work here shared those same
values and so we wrote them up and we
put them out there. Basically, it's on
all of our job applications. If you
haven't read this, please read it
because there are some people that will
not like the way that we work and you
will not be happy here cuz you're not
going to be able to change us. We want
to weed those people out early. But one
of the things that comes to mind right
now is when we think about hiring
engineers, we talk a lot about the
difference between a product developer
and a software engineer, right? A
software engineer is someone who enjoys
writing code for the sake of it. And a a
product developer is someone who really
wants to deliver value to the world and
they view software as a mechanism that
allows them to do that. And so we really
want to find the people who are driven
not by you know writing the perfect
abstract function but someone who who
really wants to solve user problems and
you know is also capable of of writing
the code. You know one of the other
things that we do is we we don't follow
any like agile scrum methodologies or
anything like that. We actually tried
when we were first starting out first
starting to scale our engineering org.
We sent our people to product owner
training and hired a scrum master and
all that stuff. And what we found was
that it took our highly creative
software engineers which because writing
software is fundamentally creative.
You're you're taking something from
nothing. People think of it as something
that's just for nerds. It's really not
that. It is a just as creative as
product design. And what it did was it
it took these creative people and it
turned them into like ticket taking task
monkeys. You know, here's the
requirements. you build this and only
this. And it eliminated kind of the back
and forth that we had where, you know,
someone might ideulate on a feature. A
designer can then like kind of put
pixels to it and then when a developer
actually starts building it and and
starts playing with it, interacting with
it, realizing like, ah, this actually
this doesn't really seem like it's
having the intent that we want. And then
we're not afraid at that point. Like we
we encourage uh 11th hour changes,
right? Like just because something has
been decided upon in an earlier stage
doesn't mean that that's what we have to
ship to the user. And we tell people all
the time it's like hey if we get to the
end stage of something we've spent you
know months working on this and it's not
the right fit we're not going to ship
it. We're not afraid to go back to the
drawing board and change it. That can be
really frustrating for some folks. It's
something that is really kind of baked
in into our process. One thing you told
me in preparation for the podcast is
that teaching.com thinks about kids
products differently and you think about
the difference between kind of parent
involved learning versus kind of
babysitting edutainment. Not to be too
derogatory on that on the babysitting
edutainment side of things because there
there is value in you know my kids use
educational apps actually I bought them
subscriptions to chat GPT and I've seen
them more and more like talking to chat
GPT creating their own images like
there's a there's room for kids to
explore on their own but I love this
idea of parent involved learning. So so
tell me about that philosophy and then
how that plays out in the product. So
with Reading.com specifically, we were
doing the research trying to figure out
what this product was going to be. One
thing became really clear to us and
there's no area of like child education
that's more well researched than reading
education. So the literature out there,
there's just tons of it and it's there
are some very clear this is the right
way to do things when it comes to to
that research. And one of the things
that we learned was that children will
not learn to read on their own and they
won't learn passively. And so because of
where we're at kind of from a it's kind
of two things, right? It's it's a
technical limitation, right? Like when
we talk about a child learning to sound
out the word Matt, for instance, you
ever heard a three-year-old? I've got
four kids myself. So you got
three-year-old trying to sound that out
going,
"Matt, the AI isn't good enough at this
point to know whether or not the child
did that correctly and to give it
feedback, right?" And so we when we sat
down to build this, we're like, there's
no technical only solution here. What we
really need is somebody sitting next to
the child being able to give the child
that feedback. And then because that's
what the research showed was that
children need to be directly instructed
on how to read, we just decided that
that was going to be an actual value for
us. And so now even if not if, but when
the AI becomes good enough to interpret
the children sounding things out, we're
not going to add that to the app because
there are plenty of apps out there that,
like I said, I got four kids. You need
some peace and quiet. You don't want to
feel bad about it. you give them an iPad
with some educational games on it and
you're able to get some stuff done.
There's nothing wrong with that. Done
that plenty of times myself. But the
trap that we fall into as parents is
thinking that they are actually going to
learn to read just from doing that. And
the research is very clear that the vast
majority of kids will not learn to read
that way. And we wanted to build
something that was truly effective. And
so I think having a parent and a child
sit down together has all these
different benefits, right? It
facilitates the child's better like
healthy understanding of screen time,
allows for some snuggle time on the
couch. The kid really is engaged, really
want because of course every kid wants
to look at a screen and so you say,
"Hey, want to come sit next to me and do
reading.com lessons?" And they're like,
"Yeah, absolutely." You're bonding with
them. they're learning healthy
boundaries because then again at the end
you are able to turn it off and say,
"Okay, now it's time to do something
else." It just increases the
effectiveness so much more. And even if
it's not with an app that's specifically
designed like ours is for a parent and a
child to do it
together, as a parent, you sit down and
use that app with your child. Like let's
say it's a math app or something and you
doing it with the child and watching
them and interacting with them over it.
One study said that that's children will
learn 19 times more effectively when a
parent is involved in the educational
app than just a child doing it on their
own. It's one of those things, you know,
as technology progresses and as AI does
get better. I think there's still going
to be a place for for these kind of, you
know, human connection via technology.
And so it it's cool that in a landscape,
as you said, of apps that are perfectly
valid and do teach kids things on their
own that there is a place for apps more
focused around direct human connection.
But really, really cool that you think
that way and really cool to have built
the product in that direction. I want to
shift gears and talk through some of the
experiments y'all run. you something you
and I talked about in person at an event
uh about a year ago and you've done so
many interesting experiments that I
think people will find fascinating. So,
let's dive into some numbers. One
experiment you talked about was a $6.99
versus $12.49 a month experiment, which
is pretty dramatic, almost double the
price. Why did you test it and what
happened? So, when we launched this app,
we started with a $699 a month price.
The reason for that was because it
seemed like a good number. We' done some
research, but not a ton on, you know,
what what the pricing should be. And so,
I think this was right back in the day,
right when Revenue Cat released the
experiments feature, the first thing we
did was we we want to test the price.
And so, we experimented with a ton of
different numbers. So, we went, you
know, we first tested a lower price,
$4.99, and we tested a bunch of
different prices all the way up to
$19.99 a month. And what we found was
that $12.49, interestingly, had the the
highest uh LTV lift. I think
$14.99 had a slightly higher
LTV, but it was really early on in our
journey. And so we really were were
conscious of balancing the reach,
especially in the kid app space. Parents
recommending things to other parents is
huge. And so we weren't necessarily
trying to ek every penny out of it. We
can clearly get some some more value out
of our users here, but we also want
there to be a very broad audience that
can continue to use the app and then
recommend it to their friends. and so
ended up at at 1249 and that's been the
the base subscription price since then
for the last probably two years or so.
Have y'all continue to do look backs on
that to make sure that the the higher
price isn't turnurning at a higher rate
that it ends up being a net negative in
the long run. Yeah, we have. And so
we've we've definitely seen that, you
know, some of the higher prices have,
you know, an initial boost in LTV, but
long-term they don't they don't pan out.
1249 is still winning after, you know,
multiple years of of looking back. Very
cool. All right. Next experiment is
monthly with trial versus monthly
without trial. Tell me about it. We
wanted to see if we could kind of push
more users to annual pricing. And so we
ran a test where, you know, we have
monthly and then annuals at like a 50%
discount. And so one cohort where they
were getting monthly with a trial,
annual with a trial, and then we were
also, you know, monthly without a trial,
trying to push people to more annual.
And it did. We did see more people use
the annual option, but ultimately
long-term it didn't work out. It ended
up with a 17% drop in realized LTV. And
so that's something that we decided not
to roll out to everyone. Do you have any
hypothesis around why that failed?
That's a great question. Users who are
more likely to go the annual route are
generally speaking higher quality users,
right? They are already more convinced
when they download the app that this is
something that they're going to use. And
the monthly users, I think, are the ones
who are more hesitant. They don't know
if this is going to work out long term.
And so I think what happened was we got
a bunch of people who were not willing
to even do a free trial on an annual
plan and they certainly weren't willing
to pay for the monthly upfront. And so
the reduction in users that we saw from
folks trying, you know, not willing to
do anything over the long term was a net
negative. That's fascinating and I'm
glad I asked that follow-up question
because this is something that I feel
like has become a little bit of an
industry standard to not give a free
trial on your monthly to push people to
the annual. But this is an interesting
counter example that if you're doing
that because that's the industry
standard now you might want to run the
test and then you know maybe again being
a higher price kind of more premium
product maybe that's the differentiating
factor where if your monthly is only
$2.99 or you know something super low
five or $4.99 you know maybe your
results would be different but yeah
really fascinating to think about it in
that way and then another experiment you
did around trial was to offer a 30-day
money back guarantee instead of a trial.
How did that go? Uh really well. Uh so
that's one that we we haven't run that
in the app. We've been running that on
all of our our web funnels. And so
instead of offering a trial, we have a
big, you know, 30-day money back
guarantee and we just ask them to pay
upfront. And that has done really well.
Obviously, it comes with much lower
conversion rates, but because we're
running paid ads to it, what it does is
it gives better signal back to the ad
networks. Specifically, most of our
campaigns are are with meta. And so,
when you're running a start trial
campaign, you know, the signal is like
all the people who are willing to start
a trial, but not necessarily all the
people who are willing to pay. And so,
you're getting a mix of like, you know,
high and low quality, high and low
intent users. But when you have a
purchaseonly funnel, every user that
gets sent back to the ad network is one
that's high intent, high quality. And so
the algorithms are able to better find
users just like that. And therefore, the
reduction in conversion rate is made up
for based on the higher quality users
and they end up sticking around longer.
And really, not many folks actually
reach out for a refund. you know, the
the friction of of doing that is
probably a little too high and you have
a really good product. If you're
struggling with trial conversion and
thinking of doing this money back
guarantee, you may have a lot more
people asking for that money back if
your product isn't actually delivering.
It seems like y'all already had very
good trial conversion because you do
have such a great product and that's
maybe a part of why this works so well
is because people don't regret making
that purchase. How do you think about
managing the different campaigns? So, it
sounds like you have kind of a a
somewhat isolated campaign that pushes
people to this versus ones that push
people to the app. Do you kind of
multi-thread campaigns in order to kind
of keep those goals separate and the the
kind of destination separate? Yeah, we
do. We have different ad set. Each ad
set is pointing at a different funnel.
our web campaigns, we have like our scan
campaigns, we have campaigns we call
prelander. And so like the different I
would say kind of attribution methods
are what separate our campaigns. But
then within the like the webfunnel
campaigns for instance, each ads set is
pointing at a different funnel that may
or may not have a trial, you know,
running different experiments on those
web funnels at different times. And so
each one of those is a distinct ad.
Gotcha. Yeah, it makes a lot of sense.
And then what works in one ad set
probably isn't going to work in the
other. And by having this kind of
multi-threaded approach, you are getting
the best of the best for each different
funnel that you've created. The next
experiment I wanted to talk about was
web to app. And it sounds like contrary
to what a lot of folks are seeing in the
industry, web to app. So I wanted to
hear what experiments you've done on web
to app and why you think it's working.
You know, I was skeptical at first as
well. I just kind of assumed that the
friction of, you know, it's just so easy
to open an app and you do an AP that
doing a purchase on the web would just
not work out that well. So what we
wanted to to do is just see is this
viable at all. So we took our existing
inapp onboarding and just replicated it
onetoone in a webfunnel and started
sending some traffic to that and I think
it was 50% better conversion to trial
and then a 30% better conversion to paid
than the same exact onboarding in the
app which was just astounding to me that
it worked so well. As we're recording
this podcast, Revenue Cat had just
released this week stats on our app to
web experiment with our app Dipsy and we
actually saw the opposite. Now, it's
different because we're sending in from
a payw wall inside the app to the web,
but we saw a pretty big drop in
conversion on the web to even starting a
free trial. And we have not gotten the
full data in yet for trial conversions.
That's going to be really fascinating. I
wonder if there is something to, you
know, being a brand because I have heard
of folks making it work, but I've also
heard of so many people struggling to
make web to app work. And, you know,
there's probably multiple factors, but I
can't help but think, you know,
reading.com when you land there, it
feels like there's like an authority
there. There's there's a brand there.
there's kind of trust that it's not some
fly by night like child reading
app.io or you know something like that.
Yeah. I do you think that plays into it
at all? Yeah, I think absolutely and I
think too the I guess brandability right
like it's really easy to remember and so
we we definitely see based on the data
that you know folks are seeing ads and
then actually just going directly to the
website not clicking on the ad. And so
when you have an easy to remember domain
like that that has this domain authority
I absolutely think that that helps and
that was a intentional strategy on our
part. That's why we also have
typing.com. And one of the future
products that we're building is
flashcards.com. And so we've invested in
these domains because first was was SEO
value and then second was just kind of
this this brand authority that comes
with it. And there's just an instant
trust that's generated when you have a
really solid domain. I'd love to to get
maybe a little more insight on your
onboarding, how you think about that,
but I imagine this whole parent centered
learning versus just kind of a digital
nanny resonates with folks as well. Is
that something you you mentioned in the
onboarding or are there specific aspects
of the onboarding that you've tested and
feel like do help people resonate and
help lead to that conversion, that
higher conversion, especially on the
web?
That's one of the challenges that that
we have with the app because there are
lots of parents who really aren't
willing to invest the time to sit down
with their kid to to do that or they
just don't really feel like they need
to. They don't understand why it's
important to do so. And so we spend a
lot of effort trying to educate parents
like I know it's inconvenient but this
is really the best thing for your child.
So we have, you know, different slides
in our kind of onboarding setup that
that kind of hint at that we when you
get into the app, we have parent focused
specific content that's explaining how
the program works and why it's important
for you to be involved. But we still get
lots of cancellation messages saying, I
shouldn't have to do this with my kid.
Why can't the app just teach me or just
teach my child on its own? And stuff
like that. So, it is definitely um a
more niche audience. When you do find
someone who's willing to to do the work
and really willing to engage, they're
willing to pay more and they stick
around longer. Yeah. Yeah, that's
fascinating. Is there a specific aha
moment, some kind of like goal that the
onboarding is centered around? Yeah,
that's a great question. It's it's
something we internally argue about a
lot. The structure of the app is there's
99 lessons that a parent and a child sit
down together. In the context of those
99 lessons, there's 60 interactive story
books. And what we found is that users
who read a book are far more likely to
stick around. The problem is, you know,
we can't have a child read a book in
their first lesson because they don't
have the skills to do so. So, you don't
get to that first book until lesson 10.
And so it's like, yeah, well, of course,
someone who's willing to do 10 lessons
is very likely to stick around and do
many more. We can't just like throw
people at a book that their kid doesn't
know how to read and expect, all right,
that's our aha moment. Like, we got it.
We nailed it. There goes activation
rates. And so we're we're trying to
figure out how do we, you know, create
an maybe a book-like experience early on
and so they can kind of catch like, oh,
this is what my kid will be doing,
capable of doing, and how do we, you
know, bump that up to the first lesson
or so. But certainly parents who
actually make it to do sit down and do
even just one lesson with their child
tend to get it and tend to say like,
"Oh, I see what's happening here and I
love it." Yeah. So maybe that aha moment
is the parent child connection. I did
want to talk about uh something you're
starting to experiment with and this is
something I think more and more apps
should experiment with and that's that
you're offering inapp purchase upsells.
So charging $9.99 for content that's
already available via the subscription.
But I I'm assuming this is for folks who
maybe are hesitant subscription hesitant
maybe is a way to put it. And how is
that working out? It's working out quite
well. We within the app, what we have is
we call them printables. And so these
are offline activities that parents can
print and actually do. There's coloring
sheets, there's little board games that
you can play with your kid, and they all
focus on different reading skills. And
so this content is available in the app
with a subscription. after they've made
a purchase or started a trial, we give
them an offer for, you know, $9.99 to
purchase access to the PDFs all at once
because otherwise the the PDFs are kind
of like dripfed as you progress through
the curriculum. You unlock the PDFs that
your kid is ready for based on their
lesson progression. And so we say, "Hey,
you pay $9.99 and we'll just send you a
link to honestly right now it's just a
Google Drive folder that we send um
people a link to and they're able to
download the PDFs directly." And we
found that about 20% of the users who
are starting a trial or completing a
purchase on the web are also opting in
to purchase this this PDF upsell.
Gotcha. Do you see a higher cancellation
rate of the trial from people who who
spend that? And so, you know, folks that
you may not have been able to monetize
anyway end up pay the $10 or or does it
maybe even end up leading to higher
retention because they see how great the
PDFs are and kind of believe more in the
product? Yeah, right now we only offer
it to people who've actually completed
their purchase or or started a trial.
And so, I don't have the trial
cancellation data right in front of me,
but I I would imagine that if that's
what we were seeing, we wouldn't still
be doing it. And so, yeah, I've just
seen that users continue to engage with
the product and yeah, I think the
printables are very high quality and
they're fantastic and also kind of
extends that experience. And I've been
actually some of my friends that use
Reading.com with their kids. It's always
fun for me when I go over for dinner and
I see, you know, the coloring sheets
from Reading.com are kind of on the wall
there. And so it kind of gives that like
brand presence also in the home is just
you've got this coloring sheet that's
just always on your wall and so you see
it and you think of it and offered a lot
of value I think. Yeah, that's really
cool. Um and then speaking of
printables, another experiment and I
know this is just getting off the ground
and so we'll have to you know revisit it
maybe in a couple of years to see how it
goes, but you're expanding into physical
products on Amazon. Why? Yeah, because
it's it's time to become a new company
again. We went from, you know, our B2B
products to our B TOC product and now
we'll start doing physical goods. Why
not? We found that a lot of our users
were requesting them to be honest. One
of the things we encourage parents to do
in between lessons is to reread the
books and so give their their children
additional practice reading these words
and they're like, "Man, I wish there was
a physical version of this book so I
wouldn't necessarily have to have more
screen time with my kid." And so after
enough user kind of interest, we decided
to to start looking into it. And
hopefully within the next 6 to 8 weeks,
we'll be selling sets of our books on on
Amazon. And I think that at first it
will be a really great LTV boost for the
users who are already subscribed and
want that additional content in the
home. But I actually think based on some
of the research that that I've been
doing that it will also work the other
way where we have folks that are looking
for books online and uh there's a number
of these different kind of sets of early
childhood readers that you can buy and
if we're able to generate enough on
Amazon that it will actually become a a
lead genen for the subscription app as
well. And so yeah, we're really excited
to to test that out and see how that
goes. Yeah, I think that's such a
fascinating strategy in that, you know,
this is where a lot of consumer
subscription is heading is that to
expand LTV, something that kids apps do
struggle with a lot is the kind of
natural churn, which is another reason
to kind of maximize LTV while you have a
family's attention. But how do you think
about that natural turn cycle and then
how do you try and both increase the LTV
which we've kind of already talked about
but then also like expand the length of
time that you're able to be a part of
these famil family's lives. That's a
certainly a unique challenge. The beauty
and the problem of reading.com is that
once your child knows how to read, they
no longer need the app, right? So, you
know, we succeed and we work ourselves
out of a job. That is challenging. The
app works really well for kids who are
like age 3 to 8. For families with
multiple children, we can certainly have
a long lifespan there, but really the
curriculum if you know if you start with
your kid at at age three, it will
probably be really challenging and you
might be around a longer period of time
because you're going to reach kind of
these natural developmental breaks where
there's a skill that the child just
isn't quite ready for. And we've seen
that people will just not open the app
for six months, keep paying for it, and
then, you know, start using it again six
months down the road. And so the younger
the child is typically the longer they
stick around. For those older kids, it's
harder because we have a placement
assessment that will, you know, you can
answer a couple of questions and it will
kind of skip some of the more basic
parts of the lessons. And you know,
obviously at that point there's even
less content for them to to go through.
And so one of the things that we're
we're focused on in addition to just
general improvements to retain more
users and improve engagement of the
folks that are kind of still in the
target window. We're going to be
expanding our curriculum because right
now the the app can take a child from
not knowing their alphabet to reading at
about an early second grade level. And
there's no reason why we can't expand
that to like an early third grade level
because in third grade the way that
children relate to reading fundamentally
changes. They shift from learning to
read to reading to learn. And so it
becomes a lot less about the core skills
of decoding words and more about
comprehension, which is really that's
kind of the holy grail of of reading
apps because that continues for a really
long time. Right now, Reading.com is one
app, but there's no reason why it can't
be a suite of apps that are specifically
targeted at different stages of uh
reading development all the way up to
even, you know, we've talked about
speedreading for adults, right? Like, so
there's all sorts of different things
that we could do with that under kind of
the umbrella of reading.com. There are a
few challenges I know you face as a kids
app and I did want to dig into those. We
actually get quite a few requests to
have more kids apps on the podcast. For
those in that niche, it's really hard.
What are some of the things that you
found especially challenging working in
kids apps and all the laws and privacy
and app store rules and everything else
that you have to kind of work around
that some folks not in the industry
don't even realize? Uh yeah, certainly
the the first challenge as a kids app in
this space was the prevention of using
thirdparty analytics. Uh so we were
unable to use Amplitude or Google
Analytics even um early on. We had to
build our own firstparty analytics tool
in order to really understand what was
going on in in the app. And then we're
able to kind of clean the data and an
anonymize it and then kind of send it
into Amplitude from there. But using
just like the the out of the box SDK
that a lot of these analytics tools
have, you just you're not going to get
through Apple review. And that's the
same with a lot of advertising
attribution products. Like there's a lot
of tooling that's out there for mobile
apps that we just can't use because
Apple won't let us because it's for kids
app. And I get it makes sense. It just
means we have to get a little creative
and find some ways to to get the
information that that we're looking for.
Like you mentioned earlier, the kind of
the app to web thing that's that's going
on right now. That would be something
that we we haven't even seriously
discussed testing it because as a for
kids app when you redirect someone to
the browser if they click on a link like
even you know like a support link in the
app for instance and you are taking them
to the web browser you have to do what
we call a grown-up gate which is just a
challenge that a child couldn't
realistically complete and so what we do
is we print out letter or numbers right
so it'll be 76 44 32 and there's a
keypad and they have to you know hit
those numbers. Obviously, these kids
can't read, so they can't complete this
challenge. But even as an adult, it's
super frustrating. There's a lot of
extra friction there. And so, if we
wanted to redirect adults to the web in
order to complete a purchase, I have to
imagine we would just have such
astronomical drop off because they just
wouldn't be willing to do that grown-up
gate. Makes sense. And, you know, this
is where I'm constantly torn. And I
think folks who listen to the podcast
regularly hear the tension. As
frustrated as we as an industry are at
Apple at different times, as a parent,
it's great to hear you say those things,
you know, because like I don't want my
kids data just hoovered up and and I
actually really appreciate Apple Arcade.
It's kind of a sleeper hit in my opinion
in that I don't want my kids using those
free-to-play manipulative games that are
pushing them to buy more coins and to
pester me on coins. And so I I don't let
them download any game unless it's Apple
Arcade and I know that they're not going
to be seeing ads. I know that they're
not going to be pressured into buying
gems or whatever and those kind of
things. So the tension between
consumerfriendly and developer friendly
is hard. There were a few other kind of
interesting takes you had that I wanted
to touch on before we wrap up. One of
them I thought was super interesting is
that you don't have any in-house
marketing employees that you very
intentionally worked with contractors.
Why is that? Yeah. um as a really small
company who can't afford a large
marketing team. We've tried in the past
to build an in-house marketing team, but
your first few marketing hires generally
need to be generalists because you can't
afford to just have a channel expert on
the full-time payroll. And you know the
kind of the saying about jack of all
trades, master of none is we've haven't
had great success with uh marketing
generalists. And so what we found to be
super successful instead is just
contracting with channel experts. They
can do it in half the time an internal
person can and your cost is lower. And
so we have someone running meta ads. We
have someone running Google ads. We had
someone running Apple ads. We have a
life cycle marketing campaign expert.
Right? like we just have created this
model where we just have like a suite of
of experts that really know their stuff
and can do it quickly and well and we
just lean on them to to do what they do
best and it's been beautiful. Do you
manage that team or who internally
supervises and and works across all
those different channels? Because I
imagine there does have to be kind of a
cohesive top- down strategy to make all
of that work. There is not a lot of
management that we do because one of the
other benefits of working with you know
experts and kind of top of their field
is that they don't require a lot of
management you know and so we have them
just integrated into our base camp and
they basically file a weekly report
saying like hey here's what happened
over the last week here's some some of
the numbers and the metrics and then
every week I sit down with the founder
and we go through those numbers and we
go through those posts and we say okay
how is this working how is that working?
What what do we need to be paying
attention to? What do we need to change?
What do we need more information on? And
we're able to really manage it that way.
And so, it's been pretty straightforward
and everyone is, you know, they're
professionals. They're great at what
they do and they they don't need a lot
of handholding. I think that's a really
fascinating way to work and it's
something I have actually talked about
on the podcast quite a few times. You
know, I've had Marcus Burke on and
Thomas Pati and Savon and Daffhne Tidman
and there's a bunch of folks in the
industry who are individual consultants
who really are the top of their game.
And one of the things I love too is that
they work across so many different apps.
And any one marketer, any one company
might try something and form a
hypothesis around why it worked, but if
you don't get to try that same thing on
five other apps, you might not realize
why it actually worked. And so I think I
think that is a fascinating way to work
and you know maybe not everybody could
pull it off but it sounds like it's
working really well for you and really
unique I think in the industry to
operate that way. So it sounds like it's
a great thing. Yeah. I mean it was
actually uh you set us down this path
when we first decided to use Revenue Cat
as our payment provider. I think I you
and I had a chat like office hours or
anything. You actually introduced me to
um Son from Growth Gems fame. We had
some conversations and you know we
brought him on as a consultant early on
and he's still with us today and he's
brought a lot of the other experts and
like exactly like you said just his his
expertise across all these different you
know just paying attention to the
subscription app space and being able to
to talk with a lot of different folks
about what's working and what's not.
Even working with other clients you know
has really been a tremendous value to us
for sure. Yeah. Unfortunately, it is
hard to replicate these days because all
of those folks I mentioned handsel on
are super busy and you know have a
two-year long wait list that they
multiple people would have to fire them
in order for you to get to work with
them today. But anything else you wanted
to share as we wrapped up? I think
that's it. Yeah, I'm just grateful for
the opportunity and yeah, it's been it's
been a fun ride. So, listen to the
podcast for years. You know, we met at a
number of events and so just excited
that we uh you know, finally made it
happen. Yeah, and thank you for coming
on. You know, we don't often get to talk
so specifically about experiments and
the results of those experiments and the
pricing decisions and things like that.
So, thanks for for being willing to to
share so much data on the podcast as
well. Yeah, for sure.
Thanks so much for listening. If you
have a minute, please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by
chat.subclub.com to join our private
community.
[Music]